<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Choi, Leena</author><author>Ward, Suzanne Capen</author><author>Schnelle, John F</author><author>Buchowski, Maciej S</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Assessment of wear/nonwear time classification algorithms for triaxial accelerometer.</title><secondary-title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</full-title></periodical><pages>2009-16</pages><volume>44</volume><issue>10</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2012</year></dates><publisher>NIH Public Access</publisher><accession-num>22525772</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1249/MSS.0b013e318258cb36</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Choi et al. - 2012 - Assessment of wearnonwear time classification algorithms for triaxial accelerometer.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22525772</url><url>http://www.pubmedcentral.nih.gov/articlerender.fcgi?artid=PMC3443532</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>PURPOSE The objective of this study is to assess the performance of existing wear/nonwear time classification algorithms for accelerometry data collected in the free-living environment using a wrist-worn triaxial accelerometer and a waist-worn uniaxial accelerometer in older adults. METHODS Twenty-nine adults age 76 to 96 yr wore wrist accelerometers for approximately 24 h per day and waist accelerometers during waking for approximately 7 d of free living. Wear and nonwear times were classified by existing algorithms (Alg([ActiLife]), Alg([Troiano]), and Alg([Choi])) and compared with wear and nonwear times identified by data plots and diary records. With the use of bias and probability of correct classification, the performance of the algorithms, two time windows (60 and 90 min), and vector magnitude (VM) versus vertical axis (V) counts from a triaxial accelerometer were compared. RESULTS Automated algorithms (Alg([Choi]) and Alg([Troiano])) classified wear/nonwear time intervals more accurately from VM than V counts. The use of the 90-min time window improved wear/nonwear classification accuracy when compared with the 60-min window. The Alg([Choi]) and Alg([Troiano]) performed better than the manufacturer-provided algorithm (Alg([ActiLife])), and the Alg([Choi]) performed better than the Alg([Troiano]) for wear/nonwear time classification using the data collected by both accelerometers. CONCLUSIONS Triaxial wrist-worn accelerometer can be used for an accurate wear/nonwear time classification in free-living older adults. The use of the 90-min window and the VM counts improves the performance of commonly used algorithms for wear/nonwear classification for both uniaxial and triaxial accelerometers.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Herrmann, Stephen D</author><author>Barreira, Tiago V</author><author>Kang, Minsoo</author><author>Ainsworth, Barbara E</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Impact of accelerometer wear time on physical activity data: a NHANES semisimulation data approach.</title><secondary-title>British journal of sports medicine</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>British journal of sports medicine</full-title></periodical><pages>278-82</pages><volume>48</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Measurement</keyword><keyword>Physical activity and exercise methodology</keyword><keyword>Physical activity measurement</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>BMJ Publishing Group Ltd and British Association of Sport and Exercise Medicine</publisher><accession-num>22936409</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1136/bjsports-2012-091410</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Herrmann et al. - 2014 - Impact of accelerometer wear time on physical activity data a NHANES semisimulation data approach(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22936409</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>BACKGROUND Current research practice employs wide-ranging accelerometer wear time criteria to identify a valid day of physical activity (PA) measurement. OBJECTIVE To evaluate the effects of varying amounts of daily accelerometer wear time on PA data. METHODS A total of 1000 days of accelerometer data from 1000 participants (age=38.7 ± 14.3 years; body mass index=28.2 ± 6.7 kg/m(2)) were selected from the 2005-2006 National Health and Nutrition Examination Study data set. A reference data set was created using 200 random days with 14 h/day of wear time. Four additional samples of 200 days were randomly selected with a wear time of 10, 11, 12 and 13 h/day(1). These data sets were used in day-to-day comparison to create four semisimulation data sets (10, 11, 12, 13 h/day) from the reference data set. Differences in step count and time spent in inactivity (&lt;100 cts/min), light (100-1951 cts/min), moderate (1952-5724 cts/min) and vigorous (≥5725 cts/min) intensity PA were assessed using repeated-measures analysis of variance and absolute percent error (APE). RESULTS There were significant differences for moderate intensity PA between the reference data set and semisimulation data sets of 10 and 11 h/day. Differences were observed in 10-13 h/day(1) for inactivity and light intensity PA, and 10-12 h/day for steps (all p values &lt;0.05). APE increased with shorter wear time (13 h/day=3.9-14.1%; 12 h/day=9.9-15.2%, 11 h/day=17.1-35.5%; 10 h/day=24.6-40.3%). DISCUSSION These data suggest that using accelerometer wear time criteria of 12 h/day or less may underestimate step count and time spent in various PA levels.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">3</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kheirkhahan, Matin</author><author>Das, Hiranava</author><author>Battula, Manoj</author><author>Davoudi, Anis</author><author>Rashidi, Parisa</author><author>Manini, Todd M.</author><author>Ranka, Sanjay</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Power-efficient real-time approach to non-wear time detection for smartwatches</title><secondary-title>2017 IEEE EMBS International Conference on Biomedical &amp; Health Informatics (BHI)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 IEEE EMBS International Conference on Biomedical &amp; Health Informatics (BHI)</full-title></periodical><pages>217-220</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>IEEE</publisher><isbn>978-1-5090-4179-4</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/BHI.2017.7897244</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7897244/</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Peeters, Geeske</author><author>van Gellecum, Yolanda</author><author>Ryde, Gemma</author><author>Farías, Nicolas Aguilar</author><author>Brown, Wendy J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Is the pain of activity log-books worth the gain in precision when distinguishing wear and non-wear time for tri-axial accelerometers?</title><secondary-title>Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport</full-title></periodical><pages>515-519</pages><volume>16</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/J.JSAMS.2012.12.002</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1440244012011310</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>OBJECTIVE
To compare three methods for assessing wear time from accelerometer data: automated, log-books and a combination of the two. 

DESIGN
Cross-sectional study. 

METHODS
Forty-five office workers wore an Actigraph GT3X accelerometer and kept a detailed activity log-book for 7 days. The automated method used six algorithms to determine non-wear time (20, 60, or 90min of consecutive zero counts with and without 2-min interruptions); the log-book method used participant recorded on/off times; the combined method used the 60-min automated filter (with ≤2min interruptions) plus detailed log-book data. Outcomes were number of participants with valid data, number of valid days, estimates of wear time and time spent in sedentary, light, moderate and vigorous activity. Percentage misclassification, sensitivity, specificity, and area under the receiver-operating curve were compared for each method, with the combined method as the reference. 

RESULTS
Using the combined method, 34 participants met criteria for valid wear time (≥10h/day, ≥4 days). Mean wear times ranged from 891 to 925min/day and mean sedentary time s from 438 to 490min/day. Percentage misclassification was higher and area under the receiver-operating curve was lower for the log-book method than for the automated methods. Percentage misclassification was lowest and area under the receiver-operating curve highest for the 20-min filter without interruptions, but this method had fewer valid days and participants than the 60 and 90-min filters without interruptions. 

CONCLUSIONS
Automated filters are as accurate as a combination of automated filters and log-books for filtering wear time from accelerometer data. Automated filters based on 90-min of consecutive zero counts without interruptions are recommended for future studies.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sathyanarayana, Aarti</author><author>Joty, Shafiq</author><author>Fernandez-Luque, Luis</author><author>Ofli, Ferda</author><author>Srivastava, Jaideep</author><author>Elmagarmid, Ahmed</author><author>Arora, Teresa</author><author>Taheri, Shahrad</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Sleep Quality Prediction From Wearable Data Using Deep Learning.</title><secondary-title>JMIR mHealth and uHealth</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>JMIR mHealth and uHealth</full-title></periodical><pages>e125</pages><volume>4</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>accelerometer</keyword><keyword>actigraphy</keyword><keyword>body sensor networks</keyword><keyword>connected health</keyword><keyword>consumer health informatics</keyword><keyword>deep learning</keyword><keyword>mobile health</keyword><keyword>pervasive health</keyword><keyword>physical activity</keyword><keyword>sleep efficiency</keyword><keyword>sleep quality</keyword><keyword>wearables</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>JMIR Publications Inc.</publisher><accession-num>27815231</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.2196/mhealth.6562</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27815231</url><url>http://www.pubmedcentral.nih.gov/articlerender.fcgi?artid=PMC5116102</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>BACKGROUND The importance of sleep is paramount to health. Insufficient sleep can reduce physical, emotional, and mental well-being and can lead to a multitude of health complications among people with chronic conditions. Physical activity and sleep are highly interrelated health behaviors. Our physical activity during the day (ie, awake time) influences our quality of sleep, and vice versa. The current popularity of wearables for tracking physical activity and sleep, including actigraphy devices, can foster the development of new advanced data analytics. This can help to develop new electronic health (eHealth) applications and provide more insights into sleep science. OBJECTIVE The objective of this study was to evaluate the feasibility of predicting sleep quality (ie, poor or adequate sleep efficiency) given the physical activity wearable data during awake time. In this study, we focused on predicting good or poor sleep efficiency as an indicator of sleep quality. METHODS Actigraphy sensors are wearable medical devices used to study sleep and physical activity patterns. The dataset used in our experiments contained the complete actigraphy data from a subset of 92 adolescents over 1 full week. Physical activity data during awake time was used to create predictive models for sleep quality, in particular, poor or good sleep efficiency. The physical activity data from sleep time was used for the evaluation. We compared the predictive performance of traditional logistic regression with more advanced deep learning methods: multilayer perceptron (MLP), convolutional neural network (CNN), simple Elman-type recurrent neural network (RNN), long short-term memory (LSTM-RNN), and a time-batched version of LSTM-RNN (TB-LSTM). RESULTS Deep learning models were able to predict the quality of sleep (ie, poor or good sleep efficiency) based on wearable data from awake periods. More specifically, the deep learning methods performed better than traditional logistic regression. “CNN had the highest specificity and sensitivity, and an overall area under the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve (AUC) of 0.9449, which was 46% better as compared with traditional logistic regression (0.6463). CONCLUSIONS Deep learning methods can predict the quality of sleep based on actigraphy data from awake periods. These predictive models can be an important tool for sleep research and to improve eHealth solutions for sleep.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>TROIANO, RICHARD P.</author><author>BERRIGAN, DAVID</author><author>DODD, KEVIN W.</author><author>MÂSSE, LOUISE C.</author><author>TILERT, TIMOTHY</author><author>MCDOWELL, MARGARET</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Physical Activity in the United States Measured by Accelerometer</title><secondary-title>Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise</full-title></periodical><pages>181-188</pages><volume>40</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2008</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1249/mss.0b013e31815a51b3</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://content.wkhealth.com/linkback/openurl?sid=WKPTLP:landingpage&amp;an=00005768-200801000-00025</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Winkler, Elisabeth A H</author><author>Bodicoat, Danielle H</author><author>Healy, Genevieve N</author><author>Bakrania, Kishan</author><author>Yates, Thomas</author><author>Owen, Neville</author><author>Dunstan, David W</author><author>Edwardson, Charlotte L</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Identifying adults’ valid waking wear time by automated estimation in activPAL data collected with a 24 h wear protocol</title><secondary-title>Physiological Measurement</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Physiological Measurement</full-title></periodical><pages>1653-1668</pages><volume>37</volume><issue>10</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><accession-num>27652827</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/0967-3334/37/10/1653</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27652827</url><url>http://stacks.iop.org/0967-3334/37/i=10/a=1653?key=crossref.2c23daf6e6f7e17f976a6911918b3c8e</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The activPAL monitor, often worn 24 h d-1, provides accurate classification of sitting/reclining posture. Without validated automated methods, diaries-burdensome to participants and researchers-are commonly used to ensure measures of sedentary behaviour exclude sleep and monitor non-wear. We developed, for use with 24 h wear protocols in adults, an automated approach to classify activity bouts recorded in activPAL 'Events' files as 'sleep'/non-wear (or not) and on a valid day (or not). The approach excludes long periods without posture change/movement, adjacent low-active periods, and days with minimal movement and wear based on a simple algorithm. The algorithm was developed in one population (STAND study; overweight/obese adults 18-40 years) then evaluated in AusDiab 2011/12 participants (n  =  741, 44% men, aged  &gt;35 years, mean  ±  SD 58.5  ±  10.4 years) who wore the activPAL3™ (7 d, 24 h d-1 protocol). Algorithm agreement with a monitor-corrected diary method (usual practice) was tested in terms of the classification of each second as waking wear (Kappa; κ) and the average daily waking wear time, on valid days. The algorithm showed 'almost perfect' agreement (κ  &gt;  0.8) for 88% of participants, with a median kappa of 0.94. Agreement varied significantly (p  &lt;  0.05, two-tailed) by age (worsens with age) but not by gender. On average, estimated wear time was approximately 0.5 h d-1 higher than by the diary method, with 95% limits of agreement of approximately this amount  ±2 h d-1. In free-living data from Australian adults, a simple algorithm developed in a different population showed 'almost perfect' agreement with the diary method for most individuals (88%). For several purposes (e.g. with wear standardisation), adopting a low burden, automated approach would be expected to have little impact on data quality. The accuracy for total waking wear time was less and algorithm thresholds may require adjustments for older populations.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhou, Shang-Ming</author><author>Hill, Rebecca A</author><author>Morgan, Kelly</author><author>Stratton, Gareth</author><author>Gravenor, Mike B</author><author>Bijlsma, Gunnar</author><author>Brophy, Sinead</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Classification of accelerometer wear and non-wear events in seconds for monitoring free-living physical activity.</title><secondary-title>BMJ open</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>BMJ open</full-title></periodical><pages>e007447</pages><volume>5</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>PUBLIC HEALTH</keyword><keyword>accelerometer</keyword><keyword>classification</keyword><keyword>non-wear</keyword><keyword>physical activity</keyword><keyword>sedentary behaviour</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>British Medical Journal Publishing Group</publisher><accession-num>25968000</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1136/bmjopen-2014-007447</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25968000</url><url>http://www.pubmedcentral.nih.gov/articlerender.fcgi?artid=PMC4431141</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>OBJECTIVE To classify wear and non-wear time of accelerometer data for accurately quantifying physical activity in public health or population level research. DESIGN A bi-moving-window-based approach was used to combine acceleration and skin temperature data to identify wear and non-wear time events in triaxial accelerometer data that monitor physical activity. SETTING Local residents in Swansea, Wales, UK. PARTICIPANTS 50 participants aged under 16 years (n=23) and over 17 years (n=27) were recruited in two phases: phase 1: design of the wear/non-wear algorithm (n=20) and phase 2: validation of the algorithm (n=30). METHODS Participants wore a triaxial accelerometer (GeneActiv) against the skin surface on the wrist (adults) or ankle (children). Participants kept a diary to record the timings of wear and non-wear and were asked to ensure that events of wear/non-wear last for a minimum of 15 min. RESULTS The overall sensitivity of the proposed method was 0.94 (95% CI 0.90 to 0.98) and specificity 0.91 (95% CI 0.88 to 0.94). It performed equally well for children compared with adults, and females compared with males. Using surface skin temperature data in combination with acceleration data significantly improved the classification of wear/non-wear time when compared with methods that used acceleration data only (p&lt;0.01). CONCLUSIONS Using either accelerometer seismic information or temperature information alone is prone to considerable error. Combining both sources of data can give accurate estimates of non-wear periods thus giving better classification of sedentary behaviour. This method can be used in population studies of physical activity in free-living environments.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Manual activPAL algorithm</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Unknown - Unknown - Manual activPAL algorithm.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.demaastrichtstudie.nl/sites/maastrichtstudie/files/manual_activpal_algorithm.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Aim This algorithm has been developed to automatically identify wake and bed times in 24 h activPAL data on an individual level on multiple days (i.e., different wake and bed times, for each day, for each participant). The accuracy of this algorithm was examined by comparing wake and bed times estimated by the algorithm with self-reported wake and bed times, using a subsample of The Maastricht Study. It has been shown that the algorithm achieved high levels of agreement. 1 A description of the algorithm can be found elsewhere.</abstract></record></records></xml>
